Finding Aid for Young Women's Christian Association of Battle Creek (Mich.) records, 1903-1958
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Young Women's Christian Association of Battle Creek (Mich.) records 1903-1958
Young Women's Christian Association of Battle Creek (Mich.)
2 linear feet
86324 Bk 2
General correspondence, board minutes, secretary's reports, photographs, and miscellanea relating to the chapter's activities; and papers, 1910-1917, concerning building program.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group is on deposit from the organization (donor no. 5 5434 ) coming to the library in October 1973.
No further additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
The Young Women's Christian Association of Battle Creek was organized March 25, 1903. In February 1918, after many years of planning and fund raising, the chapter moved into new quarters. In its early history, the chapter maintained separate departments in the area of religious education; industrial (for young women working in various industries); and girls' work (for ages 12-18 and in school). In addition, the chapter maintained a physical education program. Eventually, the chapter came to operate a summer camp at Gull Lake.
The record group is composed of general correspondence, board minutes, secretary's reports, photographs, miscellanea relating to the chapter's activities, and papers, 1910-1917, concerning building program. The records are arranged into the following series: Board minutes; Secretary's and other reports; General Correspondence; Proposed building files; Other Materials; and Photographs.
Subjects:
Battle Creek (Mich.); Michigan--Social life and customs--1911-1920.; Michigan--Social life and customs--1921-1930.; Michigan--Social life and customs--1931-1940.; Women--Michigan--Battle Creek--Societies and clubs.; Michigan--Social life and customs--20th century.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Banquets.; Battle Creek (Mich.); Building dedications.; Camps--Wisconsin.; Clothing and dress.; Dance.; Gymnasiums.; Lake Geneva (Wis.); Theatrical productions.; Wisconsin--Camps.; Women--Michigan--Battle Creek.; Women--Organizations.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Board minutes
  - 1915-1916 (Box 1)
  - 1917-1919 (Box 1)
  - 1920-1921 (Box 1)
  - 1922 (Box 1)
  - 1923-1926 (Box 1)
  - 1946-1948 (Box 1)
- Secretary's and other reports
  - Undated (Box 1)
  - 1904-1905 (Box 1)
  - 1919 (Box 1)
  - 1920-1921 (Box 1)
  - 1922 (Box 1)
  - 1923-1925 (Box 1)
  - 1926-1929 (Box 1)
  - 1930 (Box 1)
  - 1931-1932 (Box 1)
  - 1933-1934 (Box 1)
  - 1935-1936 (Box 1)
- General Correspondence
  - 1919-1920 (Box 1)
  - 1921-1922 (Box 1)
  - 1923 (Box 1)
  - 1924 (Box 1)
  - 1925 (Box 1)
  - 1926-1928 (Box 1)
  - 1929-1930 (Box 1)
  - 1931-1934 (Box 1)
  - 1935, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - 1936 (Box 1)
- Proposed building files
  - Correspondence
    - 1913 (Box 1)
    - 1914 (Box 1)
    - 1915 (Box 1)
    - 1916, 9 folders (Box 1)
    - 1917, 5 folders (Box 2)
    - 1918 (Box 2)
  - Other Papers
    - 1910-1912 (Box 2)
    - 1913 (Box 2)
    - 1914 (Box 2)
    - 1914-1915 (Box 2)
    - 1915 (Box 2)
    - 1915-1916 (Box 2)
    - 1916, 4 folders (Box 2)
    - 1916-1917 (Box 2)
    - 1917 (Box 2)
- Other materials
  - Miscellanea, 4 folders (Box 2)
  - Printed material (Box 2)
  - Minutes of the Geneva Club, 1914-1919 (Box 2)
  - Papers concerning Battle Creek Y.M.C.A.-Y.W.C.A. Committee Study, 1958 (Box 2)
  - Scrapbook, 1903-1918 (Box 2)
- Photographs
  - Banquets and other entertainment (Box 2)
  - Central City Conference, 1912-1920 (Box 2)
  - Cornerstone Laying, 1917 (Box 2)
  - Dramatics (Box 2)
  - Lake Geneva, Wisconsin, retreat (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 2)